Guide to the James Weldon Johnson Collection Manuscript Miscellany
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- H
  - HEYWARD, DOROTHY, 1890-1961
    - Letter: San Francisco, California, to Lewis M. Isaacs, Jr., 1958 Nov 8; Heyward, Dorothy, 1890-1961; 1 item (4 p.); 18 cm. (Box GROUP 2, Folder F-1)
      ALS regarding the Theatre Arts Project for East Harlem in honor of Edith J. R. Isaacs. With a printed brochure describing the Project.
      Accession: 19790205-a
  - HIMES, CHESTER B., 1909-1984
    - "This Cleveland", undated; Himes, Chester B., 1909-1984; 1 item (1 p.); 28 cm. (Box GROUP 30, Folder F-1)
      Manuscript, typescript, corrected, on the origin of Christmas.
  - HUGHES, LANGSTON, 1902-1967
    - "Shakespeare in Harlem", 1960; Hughes, Langston, 1902-1967; 1 item (37 p.); 28 cm., in paper cover, 29 cm. (Box GROUP 21, Folder F-1)
      Script, typescript mimeograph, including both "Mister Jazz" and "Shakespeare in Harlem," the latter adapted by Robert Glenn and with background music by Margaret Bonds; with original typist's cover.
      Accession: 20010620-b
    - Empty envelope, 1938 August 26; Hughes, Langston, 1902-1967; 1 item (Box GROUP 21, Folder F-2)
      Empty envelope sent from Rómulo Lachatañeré to Hughes.
      Removed from: Rómulo Lachatañeré's "!!Oh, mi´o Yemaya´!!" (Manzanillo, Cuba: Editorial "El Arte", 1938).
    - Letter: to Vernon Reyman, 1956 December 28; 2 items. (Box GROUP 21, Folder F-3)
      Purchased from Waiting for Godot Books on the Danford N. Barney, Jr. Fund, 2012.
      One TLS sent on behalf of Hughes by his secretary, Adele M. Glasgow, to Vernon Reyman thanking Reyman for his letter to Hughes and suggesting Reyman obtain a copy of Hughes' I Wonder as I Wander from Rinehart and Company. Accompanied by an envelope.
      Accession: 2012.jwj.1
    - "Crazy Hat" and related correspondence, 1945-1946; 8 items. (Box GROUP 21, Folder F-4)
      Purchased from Doris Griss on the Carl Van Vechten Fund, 2012.
      Accession: 2012.jwj.22
      Autograph manuscript, with partial lyrics for "Crazy Hat," on Hotel Times Square stationary (undated). Four TLS (1945-1946), 1 postcard, signed (1946), from Langston Hughes to Harry Belkin regarding the song. Two TLS from the Library of Congress Copyright Office (1945 October) confirming copyright.
    - Letter: to [Harry] Block, [1926 February?]; Hughes, Langston, 1902-1967; 1 item (2 p.); 27.5 cm. (Box GROUP 21, Folder F-5)
      Autograph letter, signed, possibly to Harry Block, an editor at Alfred A. Knopf, Inc. The letter discusses public events, including readings, and critical response to an unidentified book, most likely The Weary Blues (New York: Knopf, 1926). The letter also mentions [Mary White] Ovington, [W.C.] Handy, and [Witter] Bynner, among others.
      Purchased from Schulson Autographs on the Sinclair Lewis Fund, 2016
      Accession: 2016-jwj-0031
- J
  - JOHNSON, GRACE NAIL, (1885-1976)
    - Letter: Great Barrington, Mass., to Marshall Best, 1940 February 11 (Box GROUP 44, Folder F-1)
      6 items.
      Accession: 2011.jwj.1
      Gift of Glenn Horowitz Bookseller, 2011.
      One ALS, with envelope, sent to Marshall Best in which Grace Nail Johnson proposes turning the garage of Five Acres, the Johnsons' home, into a memorial for James Weldon Johnson. The letter is accompanied by three photographs of the property and a note "Suggestions for converting garage at Five Acres," outlining thirteen building projects.
  - JOHNSON, JAMES WELDON, 1871-1938
    - Letters: Great Barrington, Mass., to Rosemary Farrar, 1935, 1937; Johnson, James Weldon, 1871-1938; 2 items. (Box GROUP 3, Folder F-1)
      Two ALS, dated Sep 19, 1935, and Aug 31, 1937, with envelope. The letters praise Farrar's poetry and briefly discuss poems sent by her to Johnson.
      Accession: 19740626
    - Necktie, undated; 1 item. (Box GROUP 3, Folder F-2)
      1 necktie belonging to James Weldon Johnson given by Ollie Jewel Sims Okala to Stephen Jones, of the Beinecke Library, in gratitude for his work on the James Weldon Johnson Memorial Collection. Necktie is from Steffin (510 Madison Avenue) with a design of red and white feathers on a black background.
      Accession: 2014.jwj.3
      Gift of Stephen Jones, 2014.
    - Letters: Great Barrington, Mass., and New York, N.Y., to George Oppenheimer, 1927-1928, undated; 5 items. (Box GROUP 3, Folder F-3)
      Two ALS, dated Sep 26, 1928, and Aug 26th, n.y., with article "Books for Porch Reading" from Better Homes and Gardens (1928 July) enclosed. One TLS, dated May 18, 1927. Letters concern Johnson's book God's Trombones.
      Accession: 43551.
      Purchased from Glenn Horowitz Bookseller on the Edwin J. Beinecke Book Fund, 2011.
    - Letters: between James Weldon Johnson and Harold Guinzburg, 1925-1926; 4 items. (Box GROUP 3, Folder F-4)
      Two ALS to Harold Guinzburg, one TLS and 1 TL from Harold Guinzburg. One TL to from Guinzburg, dated Aug. 13, 1925, concerning Johnson's contribution to "The Subway Sun," an ad campaign sponsored by the New York subway system, with two ALS, dated Aug. 21 and 26, 1925, with Johnson's reply. The second ALS includes Johnson's blurb for the campaign: "I ride on the subway because it enables me to spend 15 minutes longer over my breakfast table uptown and 15 minutes longer at my desk downtown, without being late going or coming."
      One TLS from Guinzburg, dated Aug. 26, 1926, includes an AL from Johnson at the bottom, concerning dedication of God's Trombones.
      Accession: 44403
    - Letters: Great Barrington, Mass. and Fisk University, Nashville, Tenn., to Marshall Best, 1930-1937; 4 items. (Box GROUP 3, Folder F-5)
      Three TLS and 1 ALS to Marshall Best. TLS, dated July 4, 1930, regarding Saint Peter Relates and Incident and Fifty Years and Other Poems. TLS, dated April 12, 1934, concerns The Oppermanns by Lion Feuchtwanger. In his TLS, dated July 18, 1934, Johnson thanks Best for a copy of the play "Stevedore" and asks Best to sell his article provisionally titled "Interracialism, A Requisite of World Peace" (based on his address 'The Art of Being Civilized") to Harper's. ALS, dated December 10, 1937, in which Johnson plans on stopping by Best's office in order to play a recorded recitation of his poem "The Crucifixion," from God's Trombones, made "by the lady in Atlanta."
      Accession: 43553
  - JORDAN, JUNE, 1936-2002
    - "Roman Poem Number Five", 1970; Jordan, June, 1936-2002; 1 item (31 leaves); 28 cm. (Box GROUP 27, Folder F-1)
      Draft, typescript, corrected, for long poem on ruins of Vesuvius, Herculaneum, and Pompeii. Dedicated: "for Millen and for Julius and for Eddie." Inscribed: "for Clarence and Sharyn, [Major} Life! June."
      Accession: 2050
  - JULIEN, MAX
    - "Cleopatra Jones", 1972 September 8; Julien, Max; Tennant, Bill; Keller, Sheldon; 1 item (103 p.); 29 cm (Box GROUP 56, Folder F-1)
      Revised draft, typescript mimeograph, of Julien, Bill Tennant, and Sheldon Keller's screenplay for the film Cleopatra Jones.
      Purchased from Royal Books on the The Bradford F. and Lila L. Swan Fund, 2016.
      Accession: 2016-jwj-0034
- L
  - LEWIS, ANDRE
    - Photograph of Ted Joans and Bob Kaufman, [ca. 1979]; Lewis, Andre; 1 photograph: b & w; 20.3 x 25.3 cm. (Box GROUP 22, Folder F-1)
      Informal bust-length portrait showing the poets smiling broadly; Kaufman has his arm around Joans's shoulders, and Joans holds a bottle of Guinness stout.
      Accession: 20011102-b
  - LOCKE, ALAIN, 1885-1954
    - "Prospectus of the Present and Proposed Collections of Negro Americana, Africana, and Documents Relating to the Negro", 1913-1915 (Box GROUP 45, Folder F-1)
      16 items.
      Accession: 2012.jwj.11
      Typescript accompanied by two memorandum "Re: The Study of Race Literature, History, and Origins," typescripts, signed, regarding the creation of a collection at Howard University library focusing on Negro-Americana. One TLS and one TL to the President and Board of Trustees, Howard University, "Re: Negro-Americana" (February 3, 1913 and May 6, 1915), in which Locke outlines five recommendations, such as establishing a curatorship of Negro-Americana and appointing an editor of Negro-Americana. One TLS to Jesse Edward Moorland (May 20, 1915) requesting feedback on the prospectus.
      Purchased from Swann Auction Galleries on the Edwin J. Beinecke Book Fund, 2012.
- M
  - MCCLOY, TERENCE
    - "Lady Sings the Blues: The Billie Holiday Story", 1970 January 15 and 26; McCloy, Terence; 1 item; 127 p.; 29 cm. (Box GROUP 59, Folder F-1)
      Second draft, typescript mimeograph, corrected, of McCloy's screenplay for the film Lady Sings the Blues: The Billie Holiday Story. Laid in: typed letter, signed, to Leonard Lighstone from Stevie Phillips, with plot summary and reader criticism, dated 1970 January 26.
      Accession: 2016-jwj-0032
  - MCKAY, CLAUDE, 1890-1948
    - Letter: to Arthur B. Spingarn, 1942 June 29; McKay, Claude, 1890-1948; 1 item (Box GROUP 37, Folder F-1)
      One TLS in which McKay asks Spingarn if he could get him a job with the United States Office of War Information (which at that time was directed by Elmer Davis).
      Accession: 42583
  - MCWILLIAMS, RUTH E.
    - Letter: to Mrs. Willie M. Shaw, 1967 Aug 24; McWilliams, Ruth E.; 1 item (written on a clipping); 58 cm., folded to 29 cm. (Box GROUP 10, Folder F-1)
      Brief ALS to Mrs. Willie M. Shaw, mother of James E. Shaw, regarding family news. The letter is written on a newspaper clipping of an article about McWilliams, her family, and her work as a music teacher, "Ruth McWilliams -- And Her Exceptional Way," Palo Verde Valley Times, Aug 10, 1967. Accompanied by an undated AN written by James E. Shaw, about the letter, and an envelope.
      Accession: 19830214
  - MURPHY, MRS. T.J.
    - Postcard and publisher's advertisement, 1909, 1913; Murphy, T.J., Mrs.; 2 items (Box GROUP 34, Folder F-1)
      One APcS to Mrs. T.J. Murphy and 1 publisher's advertisement.
      Removed from: Dunbar, Paul Laurence. Complete Poems. New York: Dodd, Mead and Co., 1913.
      Accession: 23639
- N
  - NASH, N. RICHARD
    - "Porgy and Bess", 1958 June 12-July 25; Nash, N. Richard; 1 item (103 p.); 28 cm. (Box GROUP 54, Folder F-1)
      Fourth revised draft, typescript mimeograph, of Nash's screenplay for the film Porgy and Bess.
      Purchased from Royal Books on the Adele Gutman Nathan Theatrical Collection Fund, 2016.
      Accession: 2017-jwj-0008
  - NAYLOR, GLORIA
    - Letters: to Tom and Sylvia Paquette, 1982-88; Naylor, Gloria; 22 items. (Box GROUP 18, Folder F-1)
      Eight ALS, three TLS, five ANS, and two holograph postcards, signed, with 15 envelopes, briefly discussing her writing and speaking engagements, other travel, and personal news. Also present are photocopies of four articles written by Naylor for the New York Times, with an envelope addressed to Sylvia Paquette.
      Accession: 19920410-d
  - NEMIROFF, ROBERT
    - "To Be Young, Gifted, and Black: The World of Lorraine Hansberry in Her Own Words / adapted by Robert Nemiroff", 1969; Nemiroff, Robert; 1 item (ca. 85 leaves); 30 cm. (Box GROUP 13, Folder F-1)
      Playscript, actor's copy, typescript mimeograph. The script is annotated in manuscript, possibly by Sharon Shayne, who used the script while an understudy for a Broadway production.
      Accession: 19860501-s
- P
  - PALMER MEMORIAL INSTITUTE (SEDALIA, N.C.)
    - Correspondence and printed ephemera, 1913-1916; 10 items. (Box GROUP 43, Folder F-1)
      Purchased from Waiting for Godot Books on the Martin Greenblatt Foundation Book Fund in American Literature, 2011.
      Accession: 44179
      One TLS, dated February 1, 1915, from A. Bray, Treasurer of the Palmer Memorial Institute, to Helen F. Kimball, founder of the Sedalia Club of Brookline, Mass., which raised funds for the Palmer Memorial Institute. Six autograph postcards, signed (1914-1916), sent to Marian D. Richards, regarding the Sedalia Club. Printed ephemera, constituting promotional material for the Palmer Memorial Institute, include a brochure, "What Others Say of the Palmer Memorial Institute" (undated), a broadside reproducing a panoramic photograph of the institute's grounds (1913), and a postcard with a group portrait of the institute's faculty and students (undated).
  - PHILLIPS, J. J. 1944-
    - Letter: 1501 Blake St., No. 317, Berkeley, CA 94703, to Peter Howard, 654 Colusa Avenue, Berkeley, CA 94707, 2010 August 6; Phillips, J. J., 1944-; 1 item (2 p.); 18 cm. (Box GROUP 52, Folder F-1)
      One autograph letter, signed, on printed card, folded and with envelope. The letter discusses Howard's support, the Serendipity edition of Nigga in the Woodpile (2008), and Howard's bookstore, Serendipity Books, and mentions Annie Barrows, Andrew Hoyem, and others.
      Gift of Peter Howard, 2010
      Accession: 2010-jwj-38751
- R
  - ROBESON, ESLANDA GOODE, 1896-1965
    - Correspondence with Victor Gollancz concerning Paul Robeson, Negro and African Journey, 1929-1969 (Box GROUP 49, Folder F-1)
      1 folder.
      Purchased from R. A. Gekoski on the George B. Alvord Fund, 2014.
      Accession: 2014.ycal.5
      7 ALS and 3 TLS to Gollancz and 12 carbon TL to Robeson, dating from 1929 to 1930, concerning Paul Robeson, Negro (New York; London: Harper, 1930). 1 TLS, dated December 3, 1945, to Gollancz regarding African Journey (New York: John Day Co., 1945). Accompanied by original contracts, signed, reader's report, and third-party correspondence pertaining to royalties, permissions, and other legal matters.
- S
  - SCHUMACHER, JOEL, 1939-
    - "Capitol Cab", 1983 March 30; Schumacher, Joel, 1939-; 1 item (95 p.); 28 cm. (Box GROUP 57, Folder F-1)
      Final draft, typescript mimeograph, of Schumacher's screenplay for the film D.C. Cab. "Capitol Cab" was the working title.
      Accession: 2016-jwj-0036
  - SCHWARTZ, DELMORE, 1913-1966
    - Letter, postcard, and poems, 1938-1959, undated; Schwartz, Delmore, 1913-1966; 7 items. (Box GROUP 23, Folder F-1)
      TLS to Dwight Macdonald, 1958 Dec 30, discussing his hopes of money for work sent to Ginsburg and Hess and enclosing a poem, "Sterne," for Gloria Macdonald; APcS to Dwight Macdonald, 1938 Jun 29, from Bennington, Vermont, inviting him to stay; two-line poem on the back of an envelope for the Macdonalds, 1958 Aug; envelope addressed to Miss Hettie Cohen, 1959 Mar 4; manuscript notes on "Having Snow"; manuscript poem, "March 29, I"; and typescript poem, "Poem," beginning "The winter sky, leaden, whitened and brightened a little," with holograph first line inserted, "You are what you want to be [...]"
      Accession: 20010504-e
  - SILLIPHANT, STIRLING, 1918-1996
    - "Shaft in Africa", 1972 November 1; Silliphant, Stirling, 1918-1996; 1 item (133 p.); 28 cm. (Box GROUP 65, Folder F-1)
      Draft, typescript mimeograph, of Silliphant's screenplay for the film.
      Accession: 2016-jwj-0011
  - SIMONE, NINA, 1933-2003
    - Photograph of Nina Simone performing at the Newport Jazz Festival, 1967 July 1; Röhnert, Ursula; 1 item. (Box GROUP 69, Folder F-1)
      Gelatin silver black and white photographic print, by Berlin photographer Ursula Röhnert, of American singer, songwriter, and musician Nina Simone performing on stage at the 1967 Newport Jazz Festival. Simone is shown mid-performance holding a microphone and wearing a white, crocheted, open fishnet outfit.
      Purchased from Royal Books on the Edwin J. Beinecke Book Fund, 2019.
      Accession: 2019.jwj.0019
  - SMYTHE, HUGH H. (HUGH HEYNE), 1913-1977
    - "Are We Solving Our Race Problem? -- Some Functioning Programs", 1946 Dec 8; Smythe, Hugh H. (Hugh Heyne), 1913-1977; 1 item (2 p.); 28 cm. (Box GROUP 8, Folder F-1)
      Typescript list, briefly discussing ways of fighting racism. Annotated "Smythe's notes for Boston, Dec. 8, 1946," in manuscript in an unidentified hand.
      Removed from his Negro Masses and Leaders: An Analysis of Current Trends ([1950?]).
      Accession: 19831115
  - SOLLORS, WERNER
    - "Amiri Baraka/LeRoi Jones: The Quest for a 'Populist Modernism'", [197-?]; Sollors, Werner; 1 item (ca. 80 leaves); 28 cm. (Box GROUP 6, Folder F-1)
      Literary biography, incomplete draft, photocopy of a typescript, with corrections written by Baraka in holograph.
      Accession: 19810111
  - SPINGARN, JOEL ELIAS, 1875-1939
    - Letter: to [W. E. B.] Du Bois, 1925-08-14; Spingarn, Joel Elias, 1875-1939; 1 item (2 p.); 18 cm. (Box GROUP 50, Folder F-1)
      Draft of an autograph letter, corrected and initialed, concerning an event that evening and distribution of prizes relating to Amy Spingarn or The Crisis, the NAACP's monthly magazine edited by Du Bois.
      Purchased from Stuart Lutz Historic Documents, Inc. on the Edwin J. Beinecke Book Fund, 2016
      Accession: 2016-jwj-0017
- T
  - THURMAN, WALLACE, 1902-1934
    - "God Sends Sunday", [ca. 1929-1931?]; Thurman, Wallace, 1902-1934; 1 item (60, [53], 36 leaves); 28 cm. (Box GROUP 26, Folder F-1)
      Draft, typescript, corrected and annotated, for a three-act play about a black family living in Harlem during the Great Depression.
      Accession: 20050623-i
  - TUTUOLA, AMOS
    - "My Life and Activities", 1952 Apr 17; Tutuola, Amos; 1 item (3 leaves); 33 cm. (Box GROUP 7, Folder F-1)
      Autobiography, typescript, carbon. Annotated in manuscript: "Confidential" and "Mr. Eliot" [i.e. T. S. Eliot], possibly in the hand of Tutuola.
      Removed from his The Palm-Wine Drinkard and His Dead Palm-Wine Tapster in the Dead's Town (London: Faber and Faber, [1952]).
      Accession: 19860226-c
  - TWOMEY, MICHAEL JOSEPH
    - Postcard from an unidentified person, [ca. 1906]; Twomey, Michael Joseph; 1 item (postcard); 9 x 14 cm. (Box GROUP 19, Folder F-1)
      Postcard, addressed in manuscript in an unidentified hand to Twomey in Danielson, Connecticut, and annotated "In remembeance [sic] of James C. Burley, Hampton Institute, Hampton, Va." On the postcard is a printed photograph of the "Battalion of Cadets, Hampton Institute, Virginia."
      Accession: 19900920-d
- U
  - UNIDENTIFIED
    - "The Negro Youth" and "Manifesto", circa 1922 May; 3 items. (Box GROUP 42, Folder F-1)
      Accession: 2012.jwj.21
      Purchased from Glenn Horowitz Bookseller on the George B. Alvord Fund, 2012.
      Drafts, typescripts, corrected. Possibly written for the first convention of the Young Workers League of America (held in Brooklyn, May 13-15, 1922).
    - African Fables, circa 1864; 1 v. (circa 18 leaves); 13 cm. (Box GROUP 42, Folder F-2)
      Autograph manuscript notebook with the following fables: "A Leopard and Kbagna," "The Disobedient Boy," "The Hunter and the Gazelle," "The Story of the Juwa," and "On the Origin of the Difference Between the Black and White Races."
      Accession: 44176
    - Poems, circa 1850; 1 item (2 leaves); 24 cm. (Box GROUP 42, Folder F-3)
      Accession: 2012.jwj.17
      Purchased from the William Reese Company on the George B. Alvord Fund, 2012.
      Autograph manuscript of eight anti-slavery poems. The first line for the first poem reads: "Oh give me a republic where the boast of Freedom rings. / Where white men are all citizens, the colored only things, / Where the government refuses a Government to own / Not on the ground of principles, but that of skins alone."
    - Tintype copy photograph of a drawing of an unidentified man, [circa 1860-circa 1880]; 1 item. (Box GROUP 42, Folder F-4)
      Full-plate tintype copy photograph with heavy multicolored overpainting of a seated man in a dark suit. The tintype was likely produced from a drawing or painting of an unidentified man. Tintype has overpainting throughout except for the sitter's head. Plate may have been previously framed as overpainting shows evidence of an oval mat.
      Purchased from William Reese Co. (Swann Galleries' sale, 2009 February 26, lot 355) on the Edwin J. Beinecke Book Fund, 2009.
      Accession: 2009-jwj-28008
- V
  - VIDOR, KING, 1894-1982
    - "Hallelujah!", 1928 September 15; Vidor, King, 1894-1982; 1 item (142 p.); 29.5 cm. (Box GROUP 60, Folder F-1)
      Draft, typescript carbon, corrected, of Vidor's screenplay for the film Hallelujah!, with continuity by Wanda Tuchock.
      Accession: 2016-jwj-0028
  - VAN VECHTEN, CARL, 1880-1964
    - Letter: from "Edward III", 1944 May 14; Van Vechten, Carl, 1880-1964; 1 item (Box GROUP 36, Folder F-1)
      One ALS to "Dear Carlo" from "Edward III" regarding The Clinton News.
      Removed from: The Clinton news (New York, N.Y.: Board of Publications of the General Organization of the De Witt Clinton Public High School). Autograph: Countee Cullen.
      Accession: 15520
    - Letter: 146 Central Park Avenue West, New York, New York, to Mrs. Whiteson, 1925-1961 (Box GROUP 36, Folder F-2)
      8 items.
      Accession: 2011.jwj.2
      Gift of Glenn Horowitz Bookseller, Inc., 2011.
      TLS, dated August 7, 1961. Accompanied by printed material: Press release from the National Association for the Advancement of Colored People, "Spingarn Medal Goes to James Weldon Johnson" (June 13, 1925), leaflet "Musicraft presents James Weldon Johnson" (August, 1938), leaflet for Musicraft Album No. 21 "James Weldon Johnson, Four Readings from God's Trombones (undated), press release from MacMillan Company of Canada regarding James Weldon Johnson's death (circa June 1938), "The Proposed James Weldon Johnson Memorial" by Carl Van Vechten (February 1940), "James Weldon Johnson: A Biographical Sketch" (Fisk University, circa 1938), and typescript "June 17th is James Weldon Johnson's Birthday!" (after 1938).
- W
  - WELLER, MICHAEL, 1942-
    - "Ragtime", 1980 January-1980 April 25; Weller, Michael, 1942-; 1 item (143 p.); 29 cm. (Box GROUP 66, Folder F-1)
      Third draft, typescript mimeograph, corrected, of Weller's screenplay for the film Ragtime. Stapled in is a typed letter, signed, from J. Blake Lowe, Jr. to Kellam de Forest on Dino Le Laurentiis Company letterhead, dated 1980 April 25. Copy likely belonged to uncredited pre-production assistant, "Mrs. Boriskin," with her name in holograph pencil on the title page.
      Accession: 2016-jwj-0009
  - WESLEY, DOROTHY PORTER, 1905-1995
    - Letters: from Arna Bontemps, 1948-1949; Wesley, Dorothy Porter, 1905-1995; 11 items (Box GROUP 39, Folder F-1)
      Seven TLS from Bontemps to Wesley (of the Moorland Foundation at the Howard University Library in Washington, D.C.) and four TLC of Wesley's responses. Correspondence pertains to proposed "Poets' Festival" at Howard University.
      Accession: 42586
    - Letters: from Langston Hughes, 1948-1949; Wesley, Dorothy Porter, 1905-1995; 13 items (Box GROUP 39, Folder F-2)
      Seven TLS from Hughes to Wesley and four TLC of Wesley's replies. Correspondence largely pertains to a proposed "Poets' Festival" at Howard University. Also includes typescript, signed and inscribed to Wesley, of Hughes's poem "The Backlash Blues" and a newspaper clipping about Hughes.
      Accession: 36541
  - WHITE, WALTER FRANCIS, 1893-1955
    - Notes, undated; White, Walter Francis, 1893-1955; 1 item (2 p.); 14 cm. (Box GROUP 29, Folder F-1)
      AN on N.A.A.C.P. letterhead, possibly in hand of Walter White and relating to Rudolph Fisher's The Walls of Jericho.
      Removed from The Walls of Jericho (New York: A.A. Knopf, 1928).
      Accession: 19430101-bb
  - WHITNEY, SALEM TUTT
    - Letters: to Hallie May Woodson., 1929-1930; Whitney, Salem Tutt; 3 items. (Box GROUP 33, Folder F-1)
      Two TLS and one business card (for Salem Tutt Whitney). The letters offer advice and encouragement to Woodson and are written on letterhead for The Florence Mills Theatrical Association, Inc.
      Accession: 33118
  - WILSON, AUGUST
    - "Jitney", 2000 February 17; Wilson, August, 1945-2005; 1 item (111 p.); 29 cm. (Box GROUP 63, Folder F-1)